## Jonathan Lemze

An award-winning Head of Social Media, with over 15 years of experience in marketing, media & storytelling. Highly skilled in integrating Media and Creative and transforming a company's marketing ambitions into bespoke Social-First campaigns that provide a better return on investment (ROI)

## WORK EXPERIENCE

RAPP London

Head of Social Strategy

May 2022 - Present

- Leading social campaigns for **Samsung UK**, which were recognised on three occasions as one of TikTok's Top Ads and achieved an ROI of over £4 million.
- Developing training materials and operational workflows, such as WoW, reporting and planning for social accounts.
- Creating bespoke thought-leadership assets to expand social commerce, harness social trends and foster customer loyalty programmes in the age of social.

Starcom, Publicis London

Global Strategy Director, Freelance (project)

*February* 2022 – *April* 2022

Generated a bespoke D&I marketing roadmap for Visa Europe, which covered the entire marketing funnel, from brief
and planning to causes and targeting.

Digitas, Publicis London

Social Strategy Director, Freelance (project)

December 2021 - February 2022

Scoped out and successfully pitched the new social-media strategy while developing creative assets and establishing new
workstreams for EE's social channels.

Havas - Blink Tel Aviv, Israel

Head of Strategy, Social-First Agency

November 2017 – November 2021

- Developed organic, paid & influencer-led social marketing plans for 50+ national and international brands, including Google, SodaStream, Nestlé, Johnson & Johnson, Yoplait, Suzuki and Meatless Farm.
- Increased revenue by 43% and secured 7 new clients valued at £3 million annually.
- Led a team of nine employees and collaborated with multiple key stakeholders, including clients, partners and agency departments (i.e., creative, design, media, delivery & account management).
- Trained and empowered junior and mid-level employees so that they could thrive and rise through the ranks.

Channel 12 Jerusalem, Israel

Editor-in-Chief of the most watched news talk show in Israel, "Meet the Press"

October 2015 – November 2016

- Created the agenda and devised the content for Israel's leading live news talk show. Viewership ratings increased by 10% and saw a 5-year peak, reaching 17.7% of Israeli households.
- Orchestrated a campaign that shifted public opinion, bringing about a positive change in Israeli law and winning us the prestige "Primor" journalism award.

Channel 12 Tel-Aviv, Israel

Senior Content Editor, Channel 12 Website, App and Social Channels

December 2013 – October 2015

• Devised and produced creative assets for Channel 12 to increase its online presence, including for its website, app and social channels.

Ma'ariv Tel-Aviv, Israel

Head of News, Daily Newspaper, Website and App

*May* 2006 – *December* 2013

• Oversaw daily content creation and managed 30 professionals, including journalists, editor, designers and photographers.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Tel-Aviv, Israel
BA in Film and TV
2007-2009

## **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

**Skills:** Meta Business Suite | Google Ads | Google Suite | TikTok Ads Manager | TikTok Creator Marketplace | Adobe Photoshop | Microsoft Office (Excel, PowerPoint, Word) | Social Listening Tools |

Social Strategy | Content Creation | Analytics | Social Media | Scuba Diving